second meditation what is the highest
form of power and you have a guy
pointing the way for hiking you know
they're going on a hike and the guy is
pointing the way so you can remember the
photograph and then it says the limits
to the unlimited so this is a famous
expression in this long rim where they
say the unlimited has limits okay
the unlimited here means Buddha okay
Lord Buddha and the idea is that even
Lord Buddha has limits okay and what do
you think they are
yeah good but I can't help you unless
you have the seeds for it okay like
that's a difference between good ISM and
Christianity for example in Christianity
we believe that God made you and God can
do anything God can change you into a
turtle today can do anything but in
Buddhism we believe Buddha has limits
Buddha can't help you if you don't have
the seats okay and Buddha cannot take
bad seeds out of you Buddha cannot put
good seeds into you Buddha can only
teach okay Buddha can only teach so of
all the things Buddha does speaking is
the most important okay Buddha can only
tell you how to plant good seeds then
you have to do it yourself okay so that
means he's he or she is limited okay
they have a limit to what they can do
for you okay and they can only teach you
so when we talk about taking refuge
going for protection it's limited
how much protection you can get you see
unless you plant the seeds for the
protection okay ultimately the love that
Buddhist has for you was created by you
okay by your seats okay and the
protection is created by you so when you
do the second meditation which we'll do
together it's thinking about what I have
to do to get protection okay I have to
do something from my side to get
protection okay probably it has to do
with helping other people have
protection okay
like if you ignore people whose country
is being demolished and tell them they
can't come here then you can't expect
protection for yourself okay things like
that okay third meditation and by the
way it's my goal to go through all these
I think it's 27 meditations in the next
two days even before we reach them in
the text okay and then some of them we
will reach in the text after your
retreat after your mini in between but I
want you to meditate on them while
you're you're in your three-day which
yeah there are 27 meditations basically
okay